https://www.truelens.co.uk/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
You Are Here:
True Lens Services Limited
Privacy StatementWhat information do we collect?
We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order,
subscribe to our newsletter or respond to a survey.
When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to
enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address or phone number. You may,
however, visit our site anonymously.
Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google's
use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their
visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the
use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy
policy.
What do we use your information for?
Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following
ways:To personalise your experience (your information
helps us to better respond to your individual needs)To improve our website (we continually strive to
improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive
from you)To improve customer service (your information helps
us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support
needs)To send periodic emails. The email address you
provide for order processing, will only be used to send you information and
updates pertaining to your order. To send periodic marketing emails. By subscribing
to our newsletter, you confirm you are the authorised owner/user of the email
address submitted and consent to receive marketing emails pertaining to TLS
updates and news, such as product announcements, recent projects, events and
company news.Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe
from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at
the bottom of each email. You have the right to access and correct your
personal information and can opt into or out of receiving promotional materials
at any time.
How do we protect your information?
We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your
personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your
personal information.
We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information
is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into
our Database to be only accessed by those authorized with special access rights
to our systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.
After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security
numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.TLS complies with
the standard procedures laid down in the General Data Protection Regulation
(GDPR) to ensure that the personal information you give us is kept secure and
processed fairly and lawfully. Do we use cookies?
Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to
your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables
the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture
and remember certain information
We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart,
understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate
data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site
experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service
providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service
providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf
except to help us conduct and improve our business.
Do we disclose any information to outside parties?
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally
identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who
assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you,
so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may
also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply
with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights,
property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information
may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.
Third party links
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products
or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and
independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability
for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to
protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy
Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years
of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are
at least 13 years old or older.
Online Privacy Policy Only
This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our
website and not to information collected offline.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this
page, send an email notifying you of any changes, and/or update the Privacy
Policy modification date below.
This policy was last modified on 6th April 2018
Contacting Us
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us
using the information below.
http://www.truelens.co.uk True Lens Services Ltd
19/20 Bank Terrace, Barwell,
Leicester, LE9 8GGsales@truelens.co.uk
+44 (0)1455 848 411TRUE LENS SERVICES (TLS)
EMPLOYEE AND PROSPECTIVE EMPLOYEE DATA FAIR PROCESSING NOTICETLS is committed to maintaining the accuracy,
confidentiality and security of your personal information. This Employee Fair
Processing Notice describes the personal information that TLS collects from or
about you, and how we use and to whom we disclose that information.What Personal
Information Do We Collect?For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal
information is any information about an identifiable individual, other than the
person's business title or business contact information when used or disclosed
for the purpose of business communications. Personal information does not
include anonymous or non-personal information.We collect and maintain different types of personal
information in respect of those individuals who seek to be, are, or were
employed by us, including the personal information contained in:CVs and applications;references and interview notes;photographs and video;letters of offer and acceptance of employment;policy acknowledgement sign-off sheets;training and personal development records;payroll information; including but not limited to
national insurance number, banking and deposit information;wage and benefit information;forms relating to the application for, or in
respect of changes to, employee health and welfare benefits; including, short
and long term disability, medical and dental care; andbeneficiary and emergency contact information.In addition to the examples listed above, personal
information also includes information such as name, home address, telephone,
personal email address, date of birth, and any other information necessary to TLS
business purposes, which is disclosed in the course of an employee's
application for and employment with TLS. As a general rule, TLS
collects personal information directly from you. In most circumstances where
the personal information that we collect about you is held by a third party, we
will obtain your permission before we seek out this information from such
sources (such permission may be given directly by you, or implied from your
actions). An example of this would be an employment reference.From time to time, we may use
the services of third parties and may also receive personal information
collected by those third parties in the course of the performance of their
services for us. In that case, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that
such third parties have represented to us that they have the right to disclose
your personal information to us.Where permitted or required by
applicable law or regulatory requirements, we may collect information about you
without your knowledge or consent.Why Do We Collect
Personal Information?The personal information collected is used and
disclosed for our business purposes, including establishing, managing or
terminating your employment relationship with TLS. Such uses include:determining eligibility for initial employment,
including the verification of references and qualifications;administering pay and benefits;processing employee work-related claims (e.g.
worker compensation, insurance claims, etc.)establishing training and/or development
requirements;conducting performance reviews and determining
performance requirements;assessing qualifications for a particular job or
task;gathering evidence for disciplinary action, or
termination;establishing a contact point in the event of an
emergency (such as next of kin);complying with applicable labour or employment
statutes;compiling directories;ensuring the security of company-held information;
andsuch other purposes as are reasonably required by TLS.MonitoringThe work output of TLS employees, whether in paper
record, computer files, or in any other storage format belongs to us, and that
work output, and the tools used to generate that work output, are always
subject to review and monitoring by TLS.In the course of conducting our business, we may
monitor employee activities and our premises and property. For example, some
areas of our promises are equipped with CCTV. Where in use, CCTV cameras are
there for the protection of employees and third parties, and to protect against
theft, vandalism and damage to TLS goods and property. Generally, recorded
images are routinely destroyed and not shared with third parties unless there
is suspicion of a crime, in which case they may be turned over to the police or
other appropriate government agency or authority. Pursuant to the TLS’s IT
Policy and your contract of employment, we have the capability to monitor all
employees' computer and e-mail use.This section is not meant to suggest that all
employees will in fact be monitored or their actions subject to constant
surveillance. It is meant to bring to your attention the fact that such
monitoring may occur and may result in the collection of personal information
from employees (e.g. through their use of our resources). When using TLS
equipment or resources employees should not have any expectation of privacy
with respect to their use of such equipment or resources.How Do We Use Your
Personal Information?We may use your personal information for the
purposes described in this Policy, or for any additional purposes that we
advise you of and where your consent is required by law we have obtained your
consent in respect of the use or disclosure of your personal information.We may use your personal information without your
knowledge or consent where we are permitted or required by applicable law or
regulatory requirements to do so.When Do We
Disclose Your Personal Information?We may share your personal information with our
employees, members, contractors, consultants and other parties who require such
information to assist us with establishing, managing or terminating our
employment relationship with you, including: parties that provide products or
services to us or on our behalf and parties that collaborate with us in the
provision of products or services to you. An example of this is the provision
of payroll services by a third-party organisation providing processing services
to TLS.Also, your personal information may be disclosed:as permitted or required by applicable law or
regulatory requirements. In such a case, we will not disclose more personal
information than is required under the circumstances;to comply with valid legal processes such as search
warrants, subpoenas or Court orders;as part of TLS regular reporting activities;to protect the rights and property of TLS;during emergency situations or where necessary to
protect the safety of a person or group of persons;where the personal information is publicly
available; orwith your consent where such consent is required by
law.Notification and
ConsentPrivacy and employment laws do not generally
require TLS to obtain your consent for the collection, use or disclosure of
personal information for the purpose of establishing, managing or terminating
your employment relationship. In addition, we may collect, use or disclose your
personal information without your knowledge or consent where we are permitted
or required by applicable law or regulatory requirements to do so.Where your consent was required for our collection,
use or disclosure of your personal information, you may, at any time, subject
to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice, withdraw your
consent. All communications with respect to such withdrawal or variation of
consent should be in writing and addressed to the Chief Executive.How is Your
Personal Information Protected?TLS endeavours to maintain physical, technical and
procedural safeguards that are appropriate to the sensitivity of the personal
information in question. These safeguards are designed to protect your personal
information from loss and unauthorised access, copying, use, modification or
disclosure.How Long is Your
Personal Information Retained?Except as otherwise permitted or required by
applicable law or regulatory requirements, TLS will retain your personal
information only for as long as it believes is necessary to fulfil the purposes
for which the personal information was collected (including, for the purpose of
meeting any legal, accounting or other reporting requirements or obligations).
We may, instead of destroying or erasing your personal information, make it
anonymous such that it cannot be associated with or tracked back to you. In
most cases your data will be deleted 6 years after you have left the company.
If you have applied to work for TLS and have been unsuccessful we will retain
your data will be deleted after 6 months.Updating Your
Personal InformationIt is important that the information contained in
our records is both accurate and current. If your personal information happens
to change during the course of your employment, please keep us informed of such
changes.In some circumstances, we may not agree with your
request to change your personal information and will instead append an
alternative text to the record in question.Access to Your Personal
InformationYou can ask to see the personal information that we
hold about you. If you want to review, verify or correct your personal
information, please contact the Chief Executive. Please note that any such
communication may be required in writing.When requesting access to your personal
information, please note that we may request specific information from you to
enable us to confirm your identity and right to access, as well as to search
for and provide you with the personal information that we hold about you. We
may charge you a fee to access your personal information; however, we will
advise you of any fee in advance. If you require assistance in preparing your
request, please contact the Chief Executive.Your right to access the personal information that
we hold about you is not absolute. There are instances where applicable law or
regulatory requirements allow or require us to refuse to provide some or all of
the personal information that we hold about you. In addition, the personal
information may have been destroyed, erased or made anonymous in accordance
with our record retention obligations and practices.If we cannot provide you with access to your
personal information, we will try to inform you of the reasons why, subject to
any legal or regulatory restrictions.Your other legal rightsData protection legislation also provides you with
certain other rights. These are not always absolute rights and must be
considered in the wider scope of the legislation. These rights are:right to erasure, also known as the right to be
forgotten. The broad principle underpinning this right is to enable an
individual to request the deletion or removal of personal data where there is
no compelling reason for its continued processing. In some circumstances this
is not an absolute right;right to restrict processing. You have the right to
‘block’ or suppress processing of personal data. Again, this is not an absolute
right and will depend on the circumstances and any other legal/statutory
obligations TLS may have;right to data portability. This is unlikely to
apply in the circumstances of employment;right to object to processing based on legitimate
interests or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of
official authority (including profiling). This is unlikely to apply in the
circumstances of employment;rights related to
automated decision making including profiling. This is unlikely to apply in the
circumstances of employment;Any questions you may have regarding the processing
of your personal data should be directed at the Chief Executive of TLS.
True Lens Services. 19/20 Bank Terrace, Barwell, Leicester, LE9 8GG. Telephone: +44 (0)1455 848 411 Sales Enquiries: sales@truelens.co.uk
Copyright © 2020. All Rights Reserved. Terms & Conditions
